

Software Engineer seeking roles in Application Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Java, JDBC, Servlet, JSP, Struts, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Current Company: IBM India Pvt. Limited Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Application Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Java, JDBC, Servlet, JSP, Struts, Spring MVC, Spring

Boot, Hibernate, MySQL, MSSQL

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Overall 3.6 years of extensive IT experience in Application Development, Enhancement, Maintenance by using Java/J2EE technologies in Disaster Recovery

Having Strong knowledge in Core Java, Data Structure, Algorithms and debugging skills (Both Frontend and Backend). Very Good in Problem

Expertise in J2EE Technologies & frameworks. Knowledge in End-End flow of the Struts, JSP, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Spring boot.

Good Knowledge in Linux Commands and experience in Virtualization. Good Knowledge in scripting language (TCL, Shell Script & PL SQL).

I can acquire knowledge in any area in short of time. Quickly can understand the application/Project flow in any corner & Interested to work in challenging task. Strong communication, collaboration & team building skills with deftness in training and supporting end users to achieve performance objectives.

Have in depth knowledge in replication technologies.

Work Experience

IBM India Pvt. Limited as Software Developer Apr 2017 to Till Date

IBM India Pvt Ltd. as Software Engineer -Java Mar 2017 to Aug 2020

Key Projects Executed

Project #1:

Project Title: IT Disaster Recovery Management Software

Project Tenure: 3rd April-2017 - 31st March 2020.

Company: IBM India Pvt Ltd.

Project Description: Sanovi Enterprise DR Management suite is the leading IT Disaster Recovery Management Software

1/22/2021

that aligns DR infrastructure to meet business defined Recovery Time and Recovery Point objectives for applications. Sanovi Disaster Recovery Management™ (DRM) combines monitoring, reporting, testing and workflow automation capabilities of complex IT infrastructure into a scalable and easy-to-use solution built on industry standards. It provides a unified IT Resilience solution for managing recovery across physical, virtual and private cloud infrastructure in the enterprise datacenters.

Works and Responsibilities:

Worked in many major and minor releases.

Understanding the Solution, design & Development.

Helping Team Member to understand the new requirement.

Full fill the customer Enhancements.

Handling the customer concerns which is highly escalated from customer side.

During the escalations managing the team resources and resolving the client issues.

Gathering the issues from client and taking to the PO/Architects to prioritize and fix it in product as part of upcoming release.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from GUDLAVALLERU ENGINEERING COLLEGE, GUDLAVALLERU in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JAVA			
JDBC, Servlet, JSP			
Struts, Spring MVC			
Hibernate			
Tomcat 7/8/9			
Apache Ant			
MYSQL, Mssql, Oracle			
HTML, XML, CSS			
JS, Shell Script, TCL Script			
Eclipse			
CRM, Red Mine, Salesforce, JIRA			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time